you can't do it you you know you can't
run you're not that big you know you
can't make it but Rudy stuck in there
and um and uh I if you if you're ever
going to see the movie I'm not going to
tell you the end but it's has a very
inspirational finish that's actually uh
a real thing that happened and um it's
just a it's just a great story about how
you should never ever give up how you if
you have a dream you got to fight for it
even when it doesn't seem possible
something you can still fight to make
something happen so I love I love U I
love that movie Rudy it's it's one of
the classics I think it's a it's a great
movie to watch especially if somebody's
looking to be inspired or something it's
just a great story so that that's one of
my favorite movies there Rudy awesome
and where can we find
you well I'm all over social media uh
I'm at one Martin Matthews so that's the
number one and then Martin Matthews so
it's
facebook.com one martinm Matthews
instagram.com one Martin Matthews same
thing on Twitter so that's where you can
find me um and um you could uh I have a
website called join Martin I have some
videos some basic concepts on financial
literacy that you can find there has a
little bio on me and why I'm in the
financial industry so so I'm I'm on
social media a lot so that's probably
the best way to reach me and um and
engage with me awesome and
uh one second here I'm just going to go
take a look at we got a lot of comments
today I hope I hope that for every
hustle Zone I can get the amount of
comments that that were left today like
this is amazing Chelsea is amazing so
let's go down to the very bottom here so
Susan Susan day said
beautiful
um uh let's see
here and we got hashtags Galore so
Chelsea says family business that's
right uh that's so great financial
literacy is key yes I agree um Dave B
says um build an Empire that allows your
future families to be suc successful and
well off um hey hey Rob I want to shout
out to Rob Dave Chelsea Carly Lambo she
says hi Ryan hi Martin
Hi and then we have Shan warell creation
of the environment you want to pass on
to your kids yeah like that's so
important I think your branding is
working well Martin um so so Chelsea
says at the horse race for me talking
about our goals they're so aligned I
knew we weren't meant to be or I knew we
weren't meant to be together then I
think she meant we were meant to
be and yeah so I and I get that sorry
and I'm dyslexic so I like she typed
weren because I noticed that too but I
think she meant
word yeah no doubt um and then uh pepper
Brooks Lopez says great example of
social entrepreneurship and the much
needed service for our community yeah no
yeah well thank you so much pepper
Brooks uh and then we have uh
wealthwave the website so please check
out Martin uh at his website there so
Chelsea says yeah I meant we were okay
and thank you for all the people that
shared I mean 50 comments that's that's
amazing uh Kurt ree says great program
Martin lots of love to you and um yeah
so we're back so yeah I um yeah thank
you so much uh Martin for for coming on
to the hustle Zone I always like you
know when people want to come on like
really they actually want to come on to
the show because it's so crazy I don't
have a time block I don't advertise I
don't do any of that you know but I
think that people I I think that I I
personally like doing the hustle Zone
because I love me people like yourself
because we may come from different
backgrounds but we all have the same
habits you know for attaining wealth and
to become successful and it's it it
doesn't matter what entrepreneur um you
meet you know when it comes to family
values when it comes to time management
when it comes to financial literacy it's
pretty much all aligned in the same
place so you know thank you so much
Martin uh for for for coming on to the
hustle Zone and uh do you have anything
else that you want to add before we go
well I do want to say thanks to you and
your audience Ryan you know thanks for
having me on here I've had a I've had
fun and you know this is what I love to
do I love to be able to share these
kinds of things with people and help
them all along the way and um so I'm I'm
always
fortunate
for e
they can't hear me sorry about that you
probably couldn't hear me I was on mute
let me say that again so welcome to the
hustle Zone my name is Ryan Perez thank
God we are editing this afterwards then
you don't have to see all of that
but um so sorry I'm just trying to tune
in
here welcome to the hustle zone so hey
okay so folks my name is Ryan RP to God
AKA The Wizard AKA Ryan Perez owner and
founder of BAC creative where we donate
free websites to entrepreneurs with
disabilities and I know some of you know
someone that experiences challenge is
that needs a jump start so you need to
get them on to my website
ww. creative.com and we will get you um
we will we will definitely get you up um
on the waiting list and you know when
when there's a free website to to uh if
we have a free website available we'll
definitely get you into a website so
today is so
important the reason why it's important
to me because
I was going through my Facebook
feed and I seen like you know I've been
kind of watching this gentleman on on
Facebook
live and there's
one uh video cast that jumped out at me
and it was him his wife and his son and
I thought it was so beautiful because
you know what I have a son and um before
my son was born I got the guitar and I
started playing the guitar for my son
because I understood that that VI uh
frequency matters I would talk to my son
in his mom's womb I would talk to him
and then when he was
born I you know the day he was born like
as soon as he came out I said hey
Malcolm how are you doing he did not cry
he heard my voice he recognized it he
did not cry I went on to promote
literacy
where I started to get him to read what
before he was
two so getting him to recognize words
but he couldn't read at that time but he
was like you know I I he is an
intelligent kid but I think that with
all the proactive measures that I took I
got him to a certain degree he started
reading he started reading words when he
was two years old started doing math
equations when he was three and then he
started to to learn about business and
financial literacy when he was five so
it it is so important because I grew up
and I didn't have that um that that
education I didn't have that attention
on me but now in the information age we
have that ability to start teaching our
kids at very young that even though we
want you to go to school Malcolm you
better go to school and you better do
well but we also want to teach our
children that that if they know how to
manage their money they could do
anything they could be janitors but if
they understand financial literacy they
could be wealthy and this gentleman and
his
wife are already instilling these values
in in their son where I seen his son or
their son on the stage telling other
people
about his his business it just you know
and teaching them how to manage their
money I think it's amazing so I want to
I like this is this is a very special
hustle zone so I just want to welcome
Martin Matthews how's it going my
brother it's going great it's going
great Ryan how are you buddy I'm doing
good I'm doing good so how do you like
that intro I love it great intro I
that's that's our brand we're a family
we're keeping it real we're sharing our
real lives how we're how we're raising a
great son and you're exactly right
financial literacy is key so important
I'm so proud of you for teaching those
lessons to your son and and
understanding the importance of how you
shape him when he's young that's so
important guys that's right so I okay so
let's dial this back now you are
straight out of Liberia so you you you
spent half your years in in Liberia and
then you spent half in um in the United
States and the reason why I bring this
up because I live in Canada everybody's
an immigrant in Canada and you know
there's a certain set of values that you
learn when you when you when you migrate
to um you know to North America and and
tell me a little bit about your
experiences from moving from from
Liberia to moving to uh United
States well you know um I always had a
dream about coming to America and I had
this dream because I grew up in a poor
African country called Liberia and I
would watch all these American movies
Ryan and what I noticed from these
American movies is people just seem to
be so happy they seem to have so many
nice things and I really liked and
wanted those nice things so I thought if
I come from this poor African country if
I could just get to America I felt like
everybody in America was rich so I said
just get to America then figure out what
you're going to do when you get there so
I you know I I convinced my dad I said
you know send me to America so I finally
made it to America after surviving a
civil war we had a war in Liberia and we
had to escape and seek refuge and so
trying just getting to America was a
dream come true and then I get here and
then I realize something and that was
this not everybody in America is Rich
and then that took me down a whole new
journey of understanding how do you
become rich how do you build wealth how
do you do these things and so that that
took me on that Journey but but I was
always fascinated by how do you build
wealth and that was because I grew up in
that poor African country Liberia is one
of the poorest countries in the world
the the people are beautiful the people
have rich in spirit and and got great
energy but you know a lot of countries
in that region that part of the world
are I just you us poverty stricken a lot
of poor people it really it really broke
my heart to see that and I really wanted
to come to America to learn how do you
build wealth how what does that mean and
how can you help somebody do that and
that was what I saw as my mission my
purpose of coming here to America and
that's why it was so important for us to
start teaching that to our son um at a
young age so that he can have every
advant AG that uh that having the
financial resources or the Financial
Freedom would give him how old were you
when you when you migrated over well I
was um I was just turning 16 years old
when I came here to America so being 16
16 years
old what do you know about creating
wealth like why would you want to create
like that's not when I was 16 years old
I was looking at the women and I was you
know just doing nothing with my life and
here you were 16 years old and you
already knew that you wanted to educate
yourself about money and wealth well it
it was it was very simply this I hated
poverty that was it I didn't know a
whole lot about I didn't know anything
about creating wealth I hated poverty
and I knew that the way out of poverty
for me was going to be me doing some
kind of business that's all I knew I
didn't know what kind of business it was
what I would end up doing but I knew
that I hated poverty and I just saw so
much pain around poverty and and I
realized that the only way you could
solve the problem of poverty is through
financial literacy and and I think
through entrepreneurship because in
Africa so many people want to start
their own businesses but they don't have
the capital don't have the little bit of
money to start their business sometimes
it's like 20 or 30 or 50 bucks for them
to start a business to take care of
their family and I said if I was rich I
could help so many people and so that
was why at a young age I would see this
all the time and um the reason why I
would see it at a young age is because
um every day there used to be a line of
people outside of my house to come and
talk to my father and ask him for
financial help so I would sit in the
corner and I would listen to their
stories and it would break my heart
every single time to learn that they
were in such bad shape financially and
some of them hadn't eaten that day or
some of them needed food for the rest of
the week or or needed to take their kid
to the hospital or their parent to the
hospital and didn't have the money to do
it so it always broke my heart so I said
I want to become rich because I wanted
to help people and so that was my drive
I I make I I don't hide the fact that I
would like to be really really really
rich and I wanted to learn how to do it
that's where it started at a young age
because I wanted to do something about
poverty that I will see every day I
realized the only way you could do that
is really if you were if you were rich
or if you had substantial resources to
help people that way that's right and I
mean and there's no a lot of people
think that the money is the root to all
evil and I and I you you know what I
mean and like I remember when I was you
know like 17 18 and trying to wrap my my
mind around um discovering wealth and
and and whatnot and people are like well
you want that much money like money's
not everything Ryan well I'm like you
know honestly it is everything because
you know the the banks take your money
you put your money into a bank you know
W with the the rules of the Federal
Reserve they can m multiply that and
they're making all kinds of money off
the the hard-earned Bucks that you put
into that to that bank account so if if
they care about money why can't I care
just as much oh you and and you need it
more than they do because they're
they're a large institution and they're
that concerned about money you are an
individual so the way I broke it down
for I break it down for a lot of people
and and I tell whenever somebody says to
me well isn't money the root of all evil
and I said No it's it's the Love of
Money it has to to do more more about
what you love and what you put your
faith in and what you put your your
energy towards and um I money is just a
tool in my in my opinion when you die
you don't get to take it with you you
got to transfer it to someone else it's
just a tool so one of the ways I started
to look at money and wealth and my
responsibility to my family was simply
this buddy it was it was look back in
the day when when you had Hunter and
gatherers you know people went out and
hunted you had to be a good Hunter hter
which me which meant you had to go out
produce you had to acquire skills to go
out there and bring home the meat so
when you go out there in our world today
because now we have civilized society
you get dressed up in nice fancy clothes
you're not running and and throwing a
spear to bring home the meat you know
you got many different ways to bring
home the meat but at the end of the day
it's still all Commerce okay you go out
there and that your your your value
towards the community was your ability
to hunt well and bring home to meet so
it's the same thing now your value
towards your community is to go out and
create value and the the marketplace
will reward you with money it's just a
medium of exchange all it means is I've
delivered massive value to the
marketplace and the marketplace says hey
we like your value we like what it is
you're doing we like what you're
delivering and we will reward you with
this money so I've always looked at
money as a great thing and then when I
get that money I got the freedom and I
got the opport Unity to choose and do
with it what I wish because I went out
there and earned it so to me that was
the way I I could think of money in a
way that that bypassed all those
shortcomings that people have with
saying hey I want to be rich or I want
to be wealthy or I'd like to have this
much money and uh and and sometimes you
really do have to be careful who you
share some of that kind of stuff with
because I remember sharing a a piece of
my financial plan with someone and this
was a guy who he's an entrepreneur so I
I thought okay let me share a piece of
my financial plan with this guy he came
and talked to me about about some of his
finances and I said let me show you one
of the things I'm doing and I share with
him this and it was a piece of something
I put into place for legacy something
I'm going to build and leave to my
children and grandchildren and then he
said he said Martin what what what what
why would you want to leave behind
over100 million because there's a plan I
put into place I didn't this is all on
paper and I showed him how how some of
the things I'm doing could allow me to
leave that much asset to my to to to to
grandchildren and he said well why would
anybody what young man why would you
want to have a100 million and I thought
well why would you not so you see even
though I thought he could understand
what I was trying to do why I would want
to leave money like that or even more is
because my grandchildren can use that to
continue to better Society with it it's
better for them to have 100 million than
it is for them to have 1 million that's
my thinking but not every everybody sees
it that way but it's so important to
have the right views around money
because if you don't you'll never
acquire it and you'll never taste the
freedom that it brings and allow you to
do all the great things people want to
do with it so did you did you make a
hundred
million no I haven't made $100 million
dollar yet I have a game plan for it
though I I have um assets that I put
into place that um if it achieve certain
returns and I I earn the the incomes I'm
I'm on track for I I I would leave um I
would leave that that um or more to to
the Next Generation I don't plan for
just myself um I'm planning for grand
kids and great grandkids I wanted to
because I had a great great grandfather
and what did my great great great great
grandfather Le me nothing and what did
he leave to my great great grandfather
and the next one and next one and leave
to my dad nothing so why do I want to do
that if I have the information and the
ability to leave something to the
generations that come after me
why would I not think of how much could
I leave to them and what's the best way
to do that so that's my game plan I'm
absolutely confident if I'm uh if I'm on
earth a certain number of years and I
produce what I'm on track to produce
I'll absolutely through the through the
assets I build and develop lead that
much to to my family my grandkids uh and
so on that's right so that being said we
live in a free country I mean well we
live we we live on a free continent I
mean for the most part I live in Canada
you live in United States uh so people
have the freedom of choice not to leave
money for their their grandchild cuz
like I've had people ask me like why do
I care like why should I leave money for
my family for the future Generations you
know and then on the flip side we have
uh guys like uh Warren Buffett that you
know they're going to give all their
wealth away to charity so
why what would you tell them to to think
why like what could you say to them so
that they can see your
Paradigm well what I would say is this
um in the case of Warren Buffett even if
he leaves he's going to leave a small
percentage to his family but a small
percentage of Warren Buffett's wealth is
is over a billion dollars so that's a a
perspective that that's different from
most people but Warren Buffett wealth uh
is not going to just be handed over to
an organiz ation it is still going to be
it's a it's just a tool he's using he's
going to use different types of trusts
and his foundation but his family is
still going to be involved in that
Foundation they're just not going to be
being able to spend the money however
they want there's going to be rules
around the foundation and what they're
going to do so he still is leaving a
legacy for his kids and grandkids and
great-grandkids because they can all
still be a part of his foundation so
wealthy people don't just leave it in
the hands of their kids and say okay go
go do what you would like they will
establish certain things while they're
still alive that would enable them to
pass it on to those to to charitable
organizations to benefit a cause that
maybe Warren believes in and um and his
children will help to run that
organization so there will still be able
to to be in control and some on some
level with some of that money so the way
I would say to have a paradigm shift
about something like that is you're
still able to help society and help your
family and put family in a position to
be able to to to do charitable causes I
give you a quick example um there's
something called a a um an incentive
trust okay so let's say I have a great
grandkid um or something or grandkid or
whatever and I want to incentivize my
grandkid to go do something that benefit
Society let's say I want to incentivize
them to go do to go work for a charity
organization versus going to the
corporate world they could go into the
corporate world where they might make
more money or they could go into a
Trevor organization where it could make
a bigger difference but maybe make less
money I could build up an estate where I
leave money into an um an incentive
trust that says I'm going to
incentivize um future Generations in my
Lany age to go do charitable works and
if they do that they can access this
money in this incentive trust you know
that's what that would be designed for
and I would leave money inside of a
trust like that so you can actually
shape and mold what you would like to
see happen long after your you're gone
based on the financial tools that you
employ today so that's what I would say
to those people you can you can do so
much great things through your family or
to society through your family um that
can really make a difference for people
yeah and and and I would say in not in
in not such an eloquent way that uh like
do you love your family
like you know I look at my son I love my
son you know I look at him and it's
unconditional love you know you you want
to make sure that um even if you're not
leaving money behind that your family
has some sort of plan for what you know
if something bad happens right if
someone gets in a in a car accident or
you know what if I become disabled and I
and no longer to you able to do the
basic things you have to have some sort
of financial plan in place um my my
friend is really deep into family
offices and protecting assets and
whatnot do you know a lot about family
offices I know a little bit about that
my my extent on that is reading about it
and speaking with attorneys and um some
of the companies I do business with have
have a an advanced case design team that
can put together and talk about when
you're working with family offices
they're designed for people who' have
accumulated a lot of wealth and they
need um they need not just one person
managing their wealth they need a team
or or as they call it a whole office
that's managing their wealth so this is
for a lot of people who require a lot of
a lot of wealth you know so somebody
like Warren Buffett will have a a family
office or have all kinds of whole teams
of people managing their wealth and it's
really because you acquire all this
wealth and then you have another problem
you know most people have the opposite
problem where they don't have enough
money some rich people have the the
exact opposite problem of that which is
I've got too not too much money because
I don't think you have too much money
I've got a surplus of money now I've got
to figure out what to do with it and so
where a family office will come into
play where you know they will help you
do those kinds of things and I think
it's really cool to be in that kind of
position because now you're thinking
about okay I've I've been very blessed
and I've I've uh I've done great things
in society I've made a lot of money now
how do I use this wealth to benefit
society and that to me is is is one of
the purposes of wealth that you get to
choose what you do with it and how you
use it to benefit Society how you use it
to help other people great that's that's
amazing
I I love the answer now um I would get
in trouble if I didn't ask this question
and I asked this to everybody else and
we kind of touched on it but I want
details yeah tell me your story you know
tell me your story give me some examples
I want to find emotional connection
because I mean you could talk to me
about financial literacy till I'm blew
in the face but you know it's not going
to make it sense to me unless I
understand the emotional connection with
you you and Building Wealth so you know
what are some experien that you remember
as a youth that you can recall visually
that you know changed your Paradigm or
at least gave you the sense of urgency
for you to uh to to change your life or
to focus on doing things to make sure
that your life uh was going to be better
well I I'll give you two two examples
Ryan the first one is I want to give you
a picture and I picture this in your
mind you're you're a young child you're
maybe 7 years old and you're sitting in
his Corner in your house and the this
dad walks in with his two little
children that's about about your age a
boy and a girl and they walked in and
their clothes are are tattered but you
can tell they're cleaning this this
father takes pride in his children and
he brings them there to talk to your
father about the challeng es they're
having in their lives and and and U he
brings his kid because he brings his two
kids because no one is there to help him
watch his two kids and so he brings them
with him because the mom passed away
during the Civil War the mom died and
this this dad is trying to raise these
children and um and they walk they walk
to come to your home to see your father
to ask him for money and then you look
at their shoe you look at their feet and
one of of them is wearing a flip flops
that has a hole in the bottom and you
can see as he walks in you can see the
hole in the bottom of it and um and and
you're watching them you're sitting in
the corner and you're watching them and
you're thinking what must their life be
like what must it be like and uh how
they placed all their Hope on your
father being able to help them with a
little bit of money that day and if he
doesn't help them with money that day
they may not eat
tomorrow and with and um that would that
story was something uh that happened in
my real life and um it was the I I uh I
saw that little boy with the hole in his
in his flip-flops and um I took my
flipflops off and I gave it to him and
he kind of clutched them close he looked
at me he looked at him he clutched them
close it was almost like he didn't want
to put them on his feet because they
were new and um it was the first time I
remember ever giving and I have a an
ebook called the give 10 project how to
give more than you ever dream possible
and I I tell that story and asked the
first time I ever gave and how it made
me feel and I said that that that boy
may have may have never remembered me or
maybe years later may not have thought
about it but that made a tremendous
impact on my life and I thought you know
I'm so I was so thankful that my dad was
in a position to be able to help these
people financially because he had the
money what if he didn't have the money
and he had to tell them I'm so sorry I
can't help you I'm so sorry I'm not in a
position to do anything for you today
that family would have walked back just
even more hopeless than when they walked
in and so that's one of the things that
I'll talk about that that I say it it
connects with why I think Building
Wealth is so important because there are
there are millions of people like that
that like that Dad and that little girl
and that little boy who are out there in
the world and no one knows them nobody
knows their name nobody knows what their
life story and so if somebody can can
help them in some way because they've
been financially successful I think that
is just an amazing thing so that's one
thing the the second thing is a it's a
personal story I tell this all the time
and I smile when I say it because if I
don't smile I'll cry and um and it's
simply this look my dad did not make it
to 60 years old he died at 59 my
grandfather didn't make it to 50 years
old my uncle did not make it to 50 years
old and my younger brother died at 25
years old
so the drive the passion the the the the
go get it now go get it done it comes
from that because the these great men in
my family didn't live to be very old and
uh I always say it I don't know how much
time any I have left here so I want to
make this impact this is why I think
about Legacy I don't just think about um
there was I heard I heard somebody say
this and that's the best way I can say
especially on the hustle Zone he said
look I don't don't hustle for my first
name I hustle for my last name I'm not
hustling for Martin I'm hustling for
that's why we talk on our live stream is
hashtag on the money Matthews the
Matthews name is what I'm hustling for
that name means something to me that
name means a whole lot to me and I I
want that name that name to mean
something for other people I want you
know that that uh my my dad passed away
maybe 8 years ago now and people still
come up to me and say you know your dad
helped me with this when I was at my
lowest point your dad helped me he made
such an impact in my life and so I
that's a legacy I want to leave behind
for future generations and I'm telling
you I can leave that Legacy much better
if I am wealthy if I can build off
because I could do so many great things
with it that I wouldn't be able to do if
I was just like anyone else or if I was
just struggling to make it or if I was
dead broke and I needed to go ask
somebody else for for help financially
that's the reason why I do it that's the
reason why financial literacy is so
important I want to help other people
get into the best financial situation
they can get in because they're a little
boy and a little girl in Africa
somewhere somewhere that they can make a
difference for that is the heart of why
I do this wow see that's this is what
the El zone is all about because I love
the energy I love because I I I think I
hit that spot because you know for Me 3
years ago so I was in a relationship
with an ex fiance and when we we broke
up that was pretty devastating for me
you know because I was trying to you see
in my life I don't have like except for
my stepfather I don't have any male
examples of of of guys that had you know
achieved anything you know and though I
love my I love you know not that I they
didn't achieve anything but they um you
know in terms of building wealth in
terms of starting businesses I didn't
see those examples around and so it hits
it hits a soft spot with me to hear you
um talk about your fathers because you
know I feel you know like it's just just
that that
awareness that how important it is for
All fathers to to be the pillars of
their families it's so important people
think that you know to be a man you got
to beat your chest like you what I mean
that's not that's not what I call being
a man a man is is is someone that has
the
vision to carry the family from one
point to the other and to bring them to
a higher level and we're talking oh
we're talking metaphysical here but
there is there's a spiritual component
about being a man and it's not to order
you know your wife to do stuff around
the house no it's about the
Vision you know and having the family
come together and build so when I hear
you talk about your fathers and I hear
you talk about your uncles you know and
I hear you talk about your son I
understand where you're coming from I
understand why that gives you the
drive right because you know we
celebrate in and and we celebrate death
we don't celebrate death we don't we we
mourn we we use a negative attribute to
it when yeah when in in but what what
you're saying is that the men in your
life gave you
life yes they passed it on to you for
you to carry on the Legacy like how does
that
feel well it's a it's a tremendous sense
of
responsibility and um and um you know I
used to say and my father my father is a
great man especially in my eyes so I
used to say if I could if I could be
half the man my father was
I would consider that a success and then
I think about it and I think my father
would say no you want to be twice the
man my father was because he gave me all
his lessons and um in the places where
he fell short I understand how he fell
short so I can correct those things in
myself so that I can be twice the man
and make twice the impact and uh do even
greater things that that that are
Generations that that it builds on top
of itself it just keeps building so that
my son can do better than I did my son
can make a bigger impact than I did and
then and then um my grandson can make an
even bigger impact than that because
they take these lessons that's passed on
from all the future Generations they
take the lessons that worked they take
the Le they see the lessons that didn't
work and then they pass so it's a it's a
tremendous responsibility and it's not
lost on me that's why I always think
what will my legacy be and that's why I
say hustle for your last name and um and
it's so important to me and what you're
saying is so spoton about men being the
pillars and um and and men having to to
carry their family to where where the
vision of where they see this family
needs to be and it's not about uh it's
not about commanding your family it's
about leading your family commanding and
leading at two different things you know
commanding means somebody has to follow
an or order leading means somebody's
willingly following you and because they
they're you're you're going somewhere
where they want to go and you know my my
wife and I we we we do a live show where
we get to talk and we get to engage it's
it's never me just saying here's what
we're going to do and giving a command
um it's very much a a partnership and um
and and she's extremely supportive in in
all the different things we want to do
and and we have the same vision of where
we want to go as a family and things we
want to do and impact we want to make in
the world and um it was very important
that I found a woman like that because
who could understand especially being
entrepreneurs and a lot of your
listeners are entrepreneurs especially
being an entrepreneur it's extremely
important uh being a father and being a
husband or even just in a relationship
that it's on the same page because you
if you know where you're trying to go
and you can articulate that to your your
significant other your your your you
know your your your boyfriend girlfriend
husband wife whoever if you can
communicate that that goes a long way in
you knowing if this person is on the
same page with you or not because the
things you're going to do to reach to
get the family to the destination where
you want to go at times will be very
very very demanding and they need to
understand that that's right and so that
leads me to my next question how did you
meet your
wife well um it's an interesting story
my wife went to a um my wife's been in
into personal development and so so have
I and so my wife went to a conference it
was a personal development conference
and it was talking about money and
mindset and all that and so she met some
people I worked with a group of people I
was working with and um they connected
and this was in San Diego and my wife
lived in Las Vegas at the time and she
she um San Diego is one of her favorite
places she's originally from Northern
California she wanted to move down to
San Diego so these people said you know
maybe this might be a career path you
might want to consider so she had she
she had previously you know 18 years old
she got she was studying for a series 7
at 18 years old she had gotten into the
financial industry for a bit and then
she got out and did some other things
she did Real Estate and did did a few
other things became a mom and so she
wanted to do some other things and
expand when she became a mom she thought
it was important to teach our son life
lessons so um so she wanted to teach him
about money and so she wanted to learn
herself and and so that's how she found
her way back into the financial industry
and uh so that group of people that I
was working with connected us together
that they thought we we we' um it'd be
great for us to get to know each other
and and it it just kind of went from
there so we we had a chance to get to
know each other and and that's where
that's where it it all happened she
she's got an entrepreneurial drive like
as I do uh she's got a drive to serve
people and she's big on family and so
all those things were very important to
me and so that that's how we we linked
up through through some some mutual
people that we knew and through this uh
through this conference that that she
went to so so always be working on
yourself because you never know you put
your spouse that way yeah cuz if you're
not working on yourself you're going to
be single and broke
right that's right exactly right you
know F keep your like you know the guys
that want to build wealth to chase after
women I mean like uh if you chase after
women first and you don't have the
wealth they're not going to chase after
you but you know if you if you keep your
mind on the grind you'll always find
somebody because you know what like
creation is all about it's all about
positive positivity and positive energy
and I'm going to ask you
so when was when did you know that you
were going to marry her like what was
the thing that clicked for
you well um I
um I go to church every every Sunday and
um and not to get all religious on you
guys but I I that's where I go every
Sunday and I used to volunteer with the
special needs kids the special needs man
I know you do some things for for for uh
disabled folks and and all and so I was
I would volunteer with special needs
kids and the thing I really want wanted
the most was um I wanted somebody who
would go to church with me and um and
Chelsea did she wanted a to she wanted
to come to church with me and she loved
what I was doing volunteering with the
kids and and uh so I think that's where
it all started and um I we talked about
family and I was I we we both gauged
each other because I was um I had a I
had uh dated you know and then going out
I really wasn't meeting the kind of
person I wanted so I was being very
careful in who I started to date
seriously so we had conversations about
what we wanted in life and it all just
lined up and uh and and my wife and I
Chelsea and I are in many ways opposites
so we complimented each other and that
that's kind of what I was looking for
and um and I always thought a a person
who could be my wife is very
self-reflective she thinks through
things and she's reflective on on um on
herself and what's going on inside her
and all that so you know I really wanted
that that in a partner somebody who
would be mature enough to be able to
reflect on on themselves and and be able
to to continue to grow and that was
something that was extremely important
so people always ask us how come you
guys have such a great relationship I've
never spent this the mon even though
we're married we spend a tremendous
amount of time together more than um
more than most couples I think you know
we we run our business together we do a
live show together we go to the gym we
go to the gym um every day we at the gym
together it's very rare that you see uh
one of us without without the other so
we spent a tremendous amount of time
together even uh even even when we sit
in our house we kind of sit next to each
other it's kind of funny we kind of sit
next to each other and know the other
day we had we had a friend of ours come
over and spend a night here and we all
went to the gym together and Chelsea
rode with a friend in the car and she
goes it felt so weird being in a
different car without
you so wow we don't have an unhealthy
attachment but it might sound that way
but we just uh we spend a tremendous
amount of time together and we get along
very well we don't always agree on
everything but we get along extremely
well and that's because we took the time
to learn about each other and and and
know what we wanted in life and because
it was so aligned that's that's when I I
really knew this is the the woman I I
want to marry wow that's amazing now
when it comes to your son and teaching
those values now I think for some kids I
you know I was actually like I'm a
single dad everybody and you know going
through this whole like I'm very
selective because I don't really have
that much time to date Etc um and and
and I have to also consider my son when
I'm when I'm dating uh because I really
want something to work
now when it comes to financial literacy
and I don't want to to be in a
relationship with someone that would
that just thinks that my son should go
to school and get an education and you
know buy a house and buy get credit
cards you know I'm pretty adamant of
someone having you know being at least
aware of it and for you to find someone
that you know believes in the same
values you know I think that's amazing
now when it comes now to your
son well you're teaching kids financial
literacy some kids are like Dad Dad
come on now like why are you teaching me
this you know and if like how open was
your son in in um
in understand or like you know kind of
you know changing his Paradigm and
learning about
wealth well you know a lot of the credit
there the initial credit there goes to
Chelsea she started um she started
teaching him at a young age when he was
six years six years old and it's because
Chelsea um really she had um there there
was a time when she was in I think in
high school or or getting out of high
school where there were things she
wanted to be able to afford like she
wanted to do her nails and do all this
stuff and she didn't have and she she
thought she could not afford to do them
but this per somebody gave her some
great advice and they said write
everything down every dollar you spend
every penny you spend write it all down
and keep track of your money so she did
that and she realized she could have she
could actually afford to do all the
things she wanted if she wasn't like
mismanaging her money or spending it on
those little things we spend money on
each day she could actually do all the
things that she wanted so she really
liked that aspect of it so when um so
around 6 years old she started to teach
William about handling and
managing handling and managing his um
his his money and so um so it was it was
because we had a a fun way to do it
Chelsea Chelsea makes a lot of things
fun she's got a lot of she's got a great
energ she loves teaching kids uh so when
something's fun and interesting people
want to learn about it look I'm in the
financial industry and I can tell you
look a lot of the financial industry is
boring it's very very boring that's why
people don't like to hear about it
nobody wants to go to a boring Financial
seminar yet the financial industry
that's what that's all they do they talk
in big numbers and charts and they make
it very boring to teach kids it's got to
be fun and engaging and exciting in a in
a way that they're going to understand
the the thing we did with one of the key
things with William is um William likes
Legos he likes to build his his Legos
and so of course when whenever we go to
the store he wants to buy Legos and so
that's his purpose for having money it's
one of his purposes for having money so
we taught him how to earn money so he
can buy Legos so then we taught him how
to start a business so he can buy Legos
what was his first business right his
first business um his first business was
something we call a snackshot so in my
office uh we've got a big office here in
my office there's a lot of people there
and so he um he decided well what can I
what can I do to earn more money because
he would do chores in the house and he
would get money but he wanted more money
than what his chores would pay him so he
said well we said well think about what
you can sell so he started he actually
did a garage sale so he sold some things
and he made some money he goes well okay
what else can I sell and so we said well
we we have a money management system for
William and one of one of the ways we
allocate his money is we have a wealth
uh wealth wallet where he puts his money
that he's going to use to build wealth
every time he gets money he divides this
into these these these uh these little
wallets we even have a video of him
explaining how it works and explaining
all that so he talk the money in his
wealth wallet and he went um just the
first thing he did he went in my office
and then he grabbed a piece of paper and
he went around he asked people what was
their favorite snack so he did market
research yeah I bought this snack for
you
so at first at first he was a little bit
nervous to go and talk to these people
but he he talked to one or two people
and then he started to he said you know
what I was I was nervous and Afraid at
first but I'm not afraid anymore I can
talk to anybody so he did market
research got the snack that they wanted
he said if I B if I purchased this snack
and I brought it here would you buy it
for me and they all say yeah it's my
favorite snack so he took all their
orders then he went into his wolf wallet
we went to the store he used his own
money to start he used he had his own
Capital cuz he had been saving his
Capital so he had he had his own Capital
to start his business so he bought these
snacks he brought it back and then he
went and and uh and made his sales so he
went and sold it to these people and um
and he created a little stand in my
office he's got a little desk where he
where he sits when he's at with me at
the office and so he puts the snack or
he leaves the snacks there he leaves the
prices on them and uh he went he did all
this during the summer and he went back
to school so during while he's at school
his snacks are still there so people
will come by and buy the snacks while
he's when he comes back to the office
he's passive income so we taught him the
concept of passive income where you can
you can set something up once and it can
continue to it can it can pay you
without you actively doing the work for
it so he really liked that and and then
we he recently started a second business
and his second business involves him
teaching kids about money so we filmed
him in a very fun and and engaging ENT
aining way teaching his money system so
then we made that video available for
for sale and and then he he gets on
Facebook live and he talks about his
videos and he talks about his videos and
people go and buy it and he makes sales
so so that's his second so he he's 11y
old he's got two businesses He's Got The
Snack Shack Shack that runs in my office
and he makes sale he doubled his money
in a week from from The Snack Shack he
got his uh he's got his his his
educational business where he teach kids
about money and it's at um kids4
wealth.com kids in the number4
wealth.com and you can even see a
preview video on there and that's his
video it's William acting he's teaching
kids so um he does he does he does a
great job that's amazing so we we got to
head to Commercial and folks this is the
hustle Zone uh this is a a place where
we get to behind the the we get beh we
we find the spirit of the entrepreneur
we try to uh find the person um behind
the the ego behind the mask because
everybody has an agenda everybody has
something to push but I I feel that with
the hustle Zone you'll be able to it it
won't be as much as a push uh when
people get to know you so that's my
fundamental value with this program and
uh this this thing is blowing up the
hustle zone is blowing up so you want to
get your commercials on the hustle zone
so hit me up if you want to start
advertising on the the hustle zones but
we're going to go to commercial break
and then we'll be back uh to to to wrap
this up so just give me one second here
and then I'm GNA ask you Martin to
mute a web design company in Calgary is
taking the concept of helping others to
a whole new level and as Robin Crawford
reports it was an Okanogan man who
inspired them to use their Tech skills
to help people with
disabilities it gives me a great
pleasure to introduce to you Michael D
Haynes a motivational speaker an
entrepreneur and a businessman Michael
Haynes is doing it all and I absolutely
love it it's the best job I've ever had
in the beginning Hayes admits that he
didn't know how to get his customer
service Consulting business off the
ground and then he met Ryan Perez with
bowai creative for every website that we
sell we donate uh free websites to
entrepreneurs with disabilities the
Calgary base company builds websites for
businesses Haynes knew he needed a
website to promote himself and Perez
knew he had the tools to help we were
always talking about working um um in
the in or doing something for the
disability for the for people with
disabilities um but we didn't know what
we were going to do and I thought that
this was a great time to um to do
something and and so we invented this
whole initiative like pretty much around
Michael bow tie creative built and
maintains an entire website for Haynes
free of charge he um put my ideas into
actions and that made my my
job so much easier it's an initiative
that the four-person company is proud of
it's especially close to PR's heart
because he himself has dyslexia I paved
my own path and that's why this this
this project means so much to me because
I want to help other people create their
paths bow tie creative is now helping
other people with mental and physical
challenges build websites across North
America all because of Michael Haynes
he's a great guy and it's fantastic
working with him and I can't wait to see
what happens next for him if you know um
anyone that has a mental or physical
disability that wants to become an
entrepreneur or you know needs to needs
help to get started in the right
direction definitely check out our
website Haynes hopes with the kind of
support offered by Perez and his team
more people will find the confidence to
reach their goals I have a challenge you
have a challenge there not person in the
life without a
challenge
I'm my challeng is more pronounced than
than yours Robin Crawford Global News
Colona and we are
back so yeah folks again ww. boty
creative.com that's B creative with the
K and if you want if you are the one if
you buy a website you will sponsor
someone that's in need that's just
looking for that push because we
personally don't want um we don't want
people to feel that they don't have a
choice you know and I think that as an
entrepreneur I we have a little bit more
flexibility in helping people helping
those in our communities because if we
have better families better communities
we'll have a better world and you know
we're going to bring back Martin
Matthews because I mean he's definitely
doing what he can for his family which I
am sure has benefited the community in
some way so um I got a whole new line of
questioning fire away okay so what do
you do for fun
well you know it's it's interesting now
um I go to the gym for fun I never used
to like going to the gym Chelsea my wife
grew up in the gym and and uh I slowly
started going and and now I actually
enjoy doing it so I like going to the
gym we work out every day Monday through
Friday and and um and we have a great
time and you know it might be sounds
funny to say but I like to read a lot so
so you know I find reading fun and I I
find learning things and another thing
is um I I don't I don't play as much as
I used to soccer but I used to play
soccer all the time I was um played
soccer in high school all through high
school and a little bit in college so
soccer is my thing sometimes William our
son and I go and kick the ball around a
little bit but but I I really enjoy that
kind of stuff we volunteer so you know
that's always fun for me so those are
the kinds of things I I like to do for
fun and things with our family that we
can all do together me Chelsea and
William we all volunteer together uh so
all those things are are a lot of fun so
that's what I do for fun what's your
favorite food what's your favorite dish
um there's something called cassava
leaves and it's a it's a Liberian dish
that is my favorite food cassava leaves
who I think we eat I'm not sure like um
we eat we definitely eat cassava but I
know that some people do um like the
cassava leaves because I mean again we
live in Canada everyone's multiculture
here so we all kinds of food so uh what
what are what's your biggest pet peeve
um people who like to tell other
people people who are
naysayers you know um I just don't like
that very much I um and I don't know if
that's a pet peeve or I just don't like
that very much if if you don't think
somebody can do something just be quiet
about it don't say anything but it's
like when you put the doubts in
somebody's Minds I really really hate
that because you're you're actually in
some way they may have been super super
confident until you open your mouth and
inent it and insert it this little seed
of doubt in them that caused them to
doubt themselves so I really hate those
naysayers the people seemingly mean well
but they just give you this advice to
played safe or or not go for it or
something I I really hate when people do
that okay so I hate naysayers but what
if someone says Hey I want to jump off I
want to do I want to jump off a plane
are you you're going to you're going to
say yeah go ahead do it what if it was
like you know someone that you loved
said that they're going to jump off a
plane you know would you would you be a
nayay or would you encourage them well
I'm a guy who like to ask questions so
the first thing I'll say are you gon to
jump off the plane with a parachute on
you
know if they say I want to jump off off
the plane with the parachute on and I
said well that might be fun maybe I'll
come with you but if somebody's going to
harm themselves I think I have a respon
that just that just tells me they pain
and I think I have a responsibility to
help them through their pain so in that
case I wouldn't um I would I would try
to help them but otherwise I would ask
the question first hey you gonna have a
parachute on or not yeah uh last
question yes what's your favorite movie
and
why favorite movie I got so many great
movies let me think of one um you know I
like the the movie Rudy that's the one
that came to my mind just Rudy Rudy now
if if you guys haven't seen it Rudy is a
story of an underdog he was a a guy who
had a dream of going to play football at
Notre Dame and Rudy is actually based on
a on a real is a based on a true story
but a guy named Rudy I think Rudy Rudy
jur is is last name I think and um and
Rudy had this dream to go play for the
Notre Dame football team and he was very
small he wasn't built for football but
he just would never give up on his
dreams so many people told him Rudy you
can't do it you you know you can't run
you're not that big you know you can't
make it but Rudy stuck in there and um
and uh I if you if you're ever going to
see the movie I'm not going to tell you
the end but it's has a very
inspirational finish that's actually uh
a real thing that happened and um it's
just a it's just a great story about how
you should never ever give up how you if
you have a dream you got to fight for it
even when it doesn't seem possible
something you can still fight to make
something happen so love I love um I
love that movie Rudy it's it's one of
the classics I think it's a it's a great
movie to watch especially if somebody's
looking to be inspired or something it's
just a great story so that that's one of
my favorite movies there Rudy awesome
and where can we find
you well I'm all over social media uh
I'm at one Martin Matthews so that's the
number one and then Martin Matthews so
it's
facebook.com one martinm Matthews
instagram.com one Martin Matthews same
thing on Twitter so that's where you can
find me um and um you could uh I have a
website called join Martin I have some
videos some basic concepts on financial
literacy that you can find has a little
bio on me and why I'm in the financial
industry so so I'm I'm on social media a
lot so that's probably the best way to
reach me and um and engage with me
awesome and
uh one second here I'm just going to go
take a look at we got a lot of comments
today I hope I hope hope that for every
hustle Zone I can get the amount of
comments that that were left today like
this is amazing Chelsea is amazing so
let's go down to the very bottom here so
Susan Susan day said
beautiful
um uh let's see
here and we got hashtags Galore so
Chelsea says family business that's
right uh that's so great financial
literacy is key yes I agree um body says
um build an Empire that allows your
future families to be suc successful and
well off um hey hey Rob I want to shout
out to Rob Dave Chelsea Carly Lambo she
says hi Ryan hi Martin
Hi and then we have Shan warell creation
of the environment you want to pass on
to your kids yeah like that's so
important I think your branding is
working well Martin um so so Chelsea
says at the horse race for me talking
about our goals they're so aligned I
knew we weren't meant to be or I knew we
weren't meant to be together then I
think she meant we were meant to
be and yeah so I and I get that sorry
and I'm dyslexic so I like she typed
weren because I noticed that too but I
think she meant
word yeah no doubt um and then uh pepper
Brooks Lopez says great example of
social entrepreneurship and the much
needed service for our community yeah no
yeah well thank you so much Peppa Brooks
uh and then we have uh
wealthwave the website so please check
out
Martin uh at his website
there so Chelsea says yeah I meant we
were okay and thank you for all the
people that shared I mean 50 comments
that's that's amazing uh Kurt ree says
great program Martin lots of love to you
and um yeah so we're back so yeah I um
yeah thank you so much uh Martin for for
coming on to the hustle Zone I always
like you know when people want to come
on like really they actually want to
come on to the show because it's so
crazy I don't have a time block I don't
advertise I don't do any of that you
know but I think that people I I think
that I I personally like doing the
hustle Zone because I love meeting
people people like yourself because we
may come from different backgrounds but
we all have the same habits you know for
attaining wealth and to become
successful and it's it it doesn't matter
what entrepreneur um you meet you know
when it comes to family values when it
comes to time management when it comes
to financial literacy it's pretty much
all aligned in the same place so you
know thank you so much Martin uh for for
for coming on to the hustle Zone and uh
do you have anything else that you want
to add before we go well I do want to
say thanks to you and your audience Ryan
you know thanks for having me on here
I've had a I've had fun and you know
this is what I love to do I love to be
able to share these kinds of things with
people and help them all along the way
and um so I'm I'm always fortunate I'm
always excited when I get a chance to
share it gives me a lot of energy to do
that I really love it so um so the last
thing I I'll say to your people is um is
you know your your family needs you
and it doesn't matter if you're a kid in
a family if you're mom or dad or how
however your family is your family needs
you and your family needs you to
understand how money works for them and
how how they how you can build something
that you can leave to the Next
Generation and that's really what what a
lot of this is all about everything we
do we must do for our children we must
do for the next generation and so on and
so forth and we we want to leave them in
a better position than we ever were and
I think that is that is if you've done
that and you if you taught them good
lessons and you left them in a better
position than uh than you were I think
that is that is considered success so um
so with that I do want to thank you so
much thanks all you guys love love love
being on the hustle Zone I enjoyed it
had a great time love talking to you
Ryan it's been it's been a lot of fun
thank you so much that's that's awesome
and what did you like about like what
what what do you like what did you like
about the experience on the house own
well you know I I like the way that you
wanted to get to the heart of of what
drives a person you know the heart
that's inside of the entrepreneur the
heart that's there that's that's um that
why why they're doing something the
purpose behind it who they are and um
and I think that was so so key the way
you asked questions and and some of the
way you made things very personal and
made made us made me feel comfortable
and and um and talked about some of the
things that's important to us like like
family and those kinds of things so that
those were the things that um that
really enjoy talking about you know a
lot of times people don't really get a
chance to know the heart of the person
but I think that was that's that's
something that's very special about you
Ryan that you you really want to know
your guests and you really want to get
to know people who are who are who are
part of your program and started become
part of your community so so I applaud
you for that and um and thank you for
making it about that oh thank you and
and and the last question I was going to
ask you before we go uh we need to have
your wife on the show
yes we can't do this
one-sided you're a unit and I also want
to interview your son you know so um you
you have my calendar link actually I'm
going to send you a new one but you have
my calendar link and you know they can
book time anytime to come on to the
hustle Zone and tell their side of the
story so I would love to I would love to
have them on um because I think it's
beautiful I just think it's awesome um
and uh we got like folks I'm going to
and this I'm going to conclude
that you know look at the nucleus or
look at you know look at the world look
at the Earth planet Earth you got this
thing in the middle of planet Earth this
this this hot
core that seems
to be the reason why we're still
alive one of the reasons and you when
you start from the core you see all the
sediments you see all the degrees that
come you know all the the all the the
degrees and the you know fossils and
everything and then you have the the
Earth that we stand on so much
pressure at the core just so that you
can see so you can live and breathe as
we are right
now Martin has demonstrated this in the
hustle Zone
and he's demonstrated that with his
actions he's demonstrated by developing
a strong
core that it everyone's life around you
becomes easy let me tell you that one
more time you start from a strong core
everyone's life around you becomes easy
you know so I want you to focus on
making sure that you have you're aligned
for Success that you have the foundation
for Success so please follow Martin go
to his website you know I think this is
important that and and and if you have
kids if they're watching too much
SpongeBob like you know Malcolm come
here for a second okay I'm going to
bring Malcolm here and Malcolm when you
were watching TV what did I tell you
when you were watching TV you're just
sitting there glued to the TV what did I
tell you uh
something something don't want stop
watching the TV too much well I didn't
say stop watching TV too much but I told
Malcolm that you know what at Daddy's
house you can do whatever you want to do
do what you want to do you want to watch
TV all day go ahead and do it but what
when it comes to going to the store to
buying toys who's going to buy it nobody
nobody cuz I ain't buying it you may get
a birthday present you may get something
but if you spend half your time watching
TV maybe the other half putting together
a
business right then you could buy those
things that you see at the to the toy
store right yeah or maybe you could go
to Disneyland right or maybe I can go to
Safeway and buy the Oreo cookies that I
wanted yeah that's right so you know
letting your kids know and I'm going to
get my son to buy the you know to buy
the course um of of Martin son's uh
course on financial literacy because I
want my son to learn about it too and
you need to get your kids involved in
Building Wealth because you never know
you know if you shape up your family now
when it comes down when when they no
longer need
you you're going to start needing
them and the the tables reverse so I
want to thank you Martin again for
coming on and see you guys next time at
the and then what what you going to do
hustle Zone well we got to get Martin to
do this at the same time yeah so see you
next time at the hustle Zone okay I
didn't like that come on Malcolm you
need to scream you got to do it again
you gotta do you gotta scream it out
loud ready okay see you next time at the
hustle Zone hle
Zone that's what I like okay so so thank
you so much folks and uh we we try to do
the hustle every day if you guys want to
come on if you're an entrepreneur and
you you have a story to tell uh please
message me I'll send you my